<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<releases>
    <release number="15">
        <title>Latest Release</title>
        <title>Diff:Jul 2011 &amp; Oct 2011</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph">This is a new full release of the Akoma Ntoso XML-based document format for
            legislative documents.
            This is the first of the 2.0 releases for this schema.&lt;/p&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn174&amp;r=174&amp;format=side&amp;path=/release/trunk/schemas2.0/akomantoso20.xsd</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas2.0/akomantoso20.xsd?spec=svn174&amp;r=174</source>
    </release>
    <release number="14">
        <title>Diff:Jul 2011 &amp; Oct 2011</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph">This a minor release with some additions and bug fixes drawn from discussions
            held at the Ravenna Legislative XML Summer School in September 2011. This is an almost backward compatible
            release.&#160; This release is the first one to exclusively use the new namespace declaration
            http://www.akomantoso.org/2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A new attribute, &lt;span class="xmlinline">number&lt;/span&gt;, has been specified for the
            metadata &lt;span class="xmlinline">publication&lt;/span&gt; element&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt;, a block-level hierarchical container, is now
            called&lt;span class="xmlinline"> blockList&lt;/span&gt;, thus freeing the name &lt;span
            class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt; to become a new hierarchical container in the main hierarchy. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Three new hierarchical containers have been added, &lt;span class="xmlinline">division&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline">sublist&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Attribute for has been added to &lt;span class="xmlinline">quotedText&lt;/span&gt; for a similar
            purpose as in &lt;span class="xmlinline">quotedStructure&lt;/span&gt;, in case of multiple quotations within
            a same &lt;span class="xmlinline">mmod&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="xmlinline">rmod&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A new element &lt;span class="xmlinline">fillin&lt;/span&gt; has been added as an inline element
            (to be probably shown as a dotted line or any other typographical characteristics to represent a fill-in
            element in a printed form, that is as an example of an actual form. It is NOT meant to be used for form
            elements as in HTML, i.e. as a way to collect input from the reader and deliver to some server-side process.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline">subheading&lt;/span&gt; can now be placed within a &lt;span
            class="xmlinline">quotedStructure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Two new elements, &lt;span class="xmlinline">extractText&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline">extractStructure&lt;/span&gt;, can now be specified in any context to express an extract
            from a different text. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Two new inline HTML elements have been added, &lt;span class="xmlinline">sup&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline">sub&lt;/span&gt;, for respectively superscript and subscript text. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn174&amp;r=174&amp;format=side&amp;path=/release/trunk/schemas2.0/akomantoso20.xsd</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas2.0/akomantoso20.xsd?spec=svn174&amp;r=174</source>
    </release>
    <release number="13">
        <title>Diff:Dec 2009 &amp; Jul 2011</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The 15 July 2011 release represents a major release, sufficiently
            different and richer than previous ones to justify a new version number and a new namespace version. Many
            modifications were introduced in intermediate tentative releases throughout 2010 and 2011.&lt;br/&gt; In
            order to allow a smooth transition to Akoma Ntoso 2.0, this release will accept and support both namespace
            declarations.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ol&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;General changes&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;Namespace declaration can be either &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0
            or http://www.akomantoso.org/2.0 &lt;/span&gt;. This is the only release to exist in both namespaces.
            Subsequent releases will only use the 2.0 namespace.&lt;br/&gt; An improved specification of the naming
            convention is presented, introducing the few elements that remained to align it to the CEN Metalex naming
            convention.&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Multi-linguism&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The specification of the human language in which the document was
            written has always been rented out to a specific part of the Akoma Ntoso naming convention, but is not
            specified anywhere in the metadata of the document, so that the metadata is not a superset of the
            information that can be derived from the document’s name, contrarily to the CEN Metalex specifications.
            Furthermore, it has not be possible, so far, to specify multiple languages for the same document, nor
            indicating exceptions to the main language of the document, nor specifying the language history of a
            document,&lt;br/&gt; In this release a number of improvements and additions was made, so that real language
            annotations can be expressed on the document.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Specifying the main language(s) of a
            document&lt;/span&gt;: the new expression-level FRBRlanguage element was added to the &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRExpression&lt;/span&gt; structure of the metadata, where the main language(s) of
            the document are specified using the codes of RFC 4646. If more than one language are present in this
            specific expression, then the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRlanguage&lt;/span&gt; element can be
            repeated.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Specifying the actual language of
            individual fragments of the text&lt;/span&gt;: text fragments in a language different from the language
            specified in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRlanguage &lt;/span&gt;needs to be wrapped in a element
            (if none appropriate exists, a span element) and the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;xml:lang &lt;/span&gt;attribute
            needs to be used in the fragment with the appropriate RFC4646 code. if two or more &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRlanguage&lt;/span&gt; elements exist, every fragment of the text needs to have its
            own xml:lang attribute according to the specifications of http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-xml/, section 2.12.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Specifying translations&lt;/span&gt;: the
            expression-level &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRtranslation&lt;/span&gt; element, available in the &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRExpression &lt;/span&gt;structure allows to specify that the document is a
            (authoritative/non authoritative/unknown according to attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;authoritative&lt;/span&gt;)
            translation from a different language (attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;language)&lt;/span&gt; made
            by some agent (attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt;) of another expression (attribute
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Attribute “pivot” is available in &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRTranslation&lt;/span&gt;
            elements to specify the pivot language for non-final translations (e.g., in a translation from Danish to
            Italian through English, two &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRTranslation &lt;/span&gt;elements need to be
            added, the first of which will have pivot=”eng” to specify the destination language of the non-final
            translation. Also, attribute language is now &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;fromLanguage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New document collection document types&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;It has recently become apparent that some new types of documents are of
            interest and need to be taken into consideration. These documents are not containers of (structured or
            semi-structured) text, but containers of documents that have their own identity and independent
            addressability. Issues of the Official Gazette, and amendment lists are clear examples of these situations.&lt;br/&gt;
            A new class of documents has therefore been created, documentCollection, with its own external structure
            (metadata, preface, conclusions and attachments), and an internal content, the collection itself, composed
            of either other Akoma Ntoso documents (including acts, bills, minutes, etc.), or interstitial containers of
            text that separate each document, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;
            &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?&gt;
            &lt;akomaNtoso&gt;
            &lt;documentCollection&gt;
            &lt;meta&gt;
            ... the metadata of the collection ...
            &lt;/meta&gt;
            &lt;preface&gt;
            ... the preface of the collection ...
            &lt;/preface&gt;
            &lt;collectionContent&gt;
            &lt;act&gt;
            &lt;meta&gt;
            ... the metadata of the first document ...
            &lt;/meta&gt;
            &lt;preface&gt;
            ... the preface of the first document ...
            &lt;/preface&gt;
            &lt;body&gt;
            ... the body of the first document ...
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;/act&gt;
            &lt;interstitial id=”int1”&gt;
            Any text is in the collection but
            belongs to no individual document
            &lt;/interstitial&gt;
            &lt;act&gt;
            &lt;meta&gt;
            ...the metadata of the second document...
            &lt;/meta&gt;
            &lt;preface&gt;
            ...the preface of the second document...
            &lt;/preface&gt;
            &lt;body&gt;
            ...the body of the second document...
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;/act&gt;
            ... other documents and interstitials...
            &lt;/collectionContent&gt;
            &lt;/documentCollection&gt;
            &lt;/akomaNtoso&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Document collections can have any number of documents and interstitial elements in
            any order, and it is possible to have interstitial elements at the beginning of the document.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Components can be present in place, or refer to them via a URI to an external
            resource, or even placed in the document in an apposite final section called components, and referred to via
            a newly introduced componentRef element. This modification affects also attachments, which can now be
            referenced in the same way via a componentRef element. Element attachment within element attachments has
            therefore been removed. Furthermore, in order to avoid ambiguity of element names, previous elements
            components and component in FRBR structures are now called componentInfo and componentData respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New Amendment document type&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;A new document type, amendment, has been added, with accompanying
            subelements amendmentHeading, amendmentContent, amendmentReference and amendmentJustification and many
            inline additions.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Time intervals&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Managing time intervals in text has been completely modified:
            attributes &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;start, end, startEfficacy&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;endEfficacy&lt;/span&gt; have been replaced with a single period attribute, and a new
            metadata section temporalData has been added, containing a list of temporalGroup elements that contain
            timeInterval elements.&lt;br/&gt; While before one would use the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;start, end,
            startEfficacy&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;endEfficacy&lt;/span&gt; attributes to specify
            the beginning and end, respectively, of in force and efficacy intervals, respectively, the procedure has now
            been considerably simplified and streamlined and modularized. In the text, a single period attribute is used
            instead of the four previous attributes, containing a reference pointing to the newly introduced &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;temporalGroup&lt;/span&gt; element in the metadata section. Each &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;temporalGroup&lt;/span&gt; contains a list of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;timeInterval&lt;/span&gt;
            elements, each specifying a time interval and a type in terms of the Akoma Ntoso ontology, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;Before: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;

            &lt;metadata&gt;
            &lt;lifecycle source="#fv"&gt;
            &lt;event id="e1" date="1997-08-29" source="#ro1" type="generation" refersTo="#LegislativeCreation"/&gt;
            &lt;event id="e2" date="2003-12-19" source="#rp1" type="modification" refersTo="#LegislativeModification"/&gt;
            &lt;/lifecycle&gt;
            ...
            &lt;/metadata&gt;

            &lt;body&gt;
            ...
            &lt;span start="e1" end="e2"&gt;"pooled fund" means a fund established by a limited liability company, other
            than an approved issuer, for purposes of pooling scheme funds for collective investment; &lt;/span&gt;
            ...
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;/xmp&gt;

            After:
            &lt;xmp&gt;
            &lt;metadata&gt;
            &lt;temporalData source="#FV"&gt;
            &lt;temporalGroup id="p1"&gt;
            &lt;timeInterval start="#e1" end="#e2" refersTo="#inforce"/&gt;
            &lt;/temporalGroup&gt;
            &lt;/temporalData&gt;
            &lt;lifecycle source="#fv"&gt;
            &lt;event id="e1" date="1997-08-29" source="#ro1" type="generation" refersTo="#LegislativeCreation"/&gt;
            &lt;event id="e2" date="2003-12-19" source="#rp1" type="modification" refersTo="#LegislativeModification"/&gt;
            &lt;/lifecycle&gt;
            ...
            &lt;/metadata&gt;

            &lt;body&gt;
            ...
            &lt;span period="p1"&gt;"pooled fund" means a fund established by a limited liability company, other than an
            approved issuer, for purposes of pooling scheme funds for collective investment; &lt;/span&gt;
            ...
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;/xmp&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&#160;

            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Time intervals can be specified either by a begin and end date, or
            with either date and a duration. The advantages of this approach are many:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;It is possible to introduce time intervals with either two dates, or a start date
            and a duration or an end date and a duration.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;It is possible to specify in force intervals, efficacy intervals and any other
            type of time information without cluttering the actual content of the document with more and more start and
            end attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Time information shared by many different elements in the document are grouped in
            a single collection, so that it becomes possible to understand at a glance how many intervals are relevant
            for the document.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt; It is possible to include different and incompatible time information details by
            different scholars without cluttering with useless information the actual content of the document.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Footnotes and out-of-lines&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;In past versions of the Akoma Ntoso standard, footnotes (element &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;note&lt;/span&gt;) and side notes (element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;outOfLine)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            were considered editorial content that are not really part of the authoritative content of the document.
            This is neither universal nor frequent. In fact, in many cases the official author of the document uses
            footnotes and out of line elements such as side notes as an additional means to convey authoritative
            content. For this reason, the notes’ model has been simplified:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;inlineNote are now called authorialNote,&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;outOfLineNotes have been removed.&lt;br/&gt; Attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placement&lt;/span&gt;
            has been added.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;num &lt;/span&gt;has been renamed &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;marker&lt;/span&gt; and has become optional, given that sometimes one does not have any
            marker whatsoever for the note.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Furthermore, note references have added a mechanism to specify exactly the
            placement of the note with re
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;gards to other elements of the document: an optional &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase &lt;/span&gt;attribute has been added, which contains a local &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;href&lt;/span&gt; (i.e. a #id reference) to the element near which the note should be
            placed.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p style="margin-left: 40px; text-align: justify;"&gt;To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note at the end of a document, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placement="bottom"&lt;/span&gt;
            and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase="#[document ID]"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note at the end of a structure, including quotations, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;placement="bottom"&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase="#[structure
            ID].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note inline, in the closest position to the note reference, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;placement="inline"&lt;/span&gt; and no &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note inline in the closest position to a specific structure, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;placement="inline"&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase="#[structure
            ID]"&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note on the side, in the position of the note reference, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt; placement="side" &lt;/span&gt;and no &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To place a note on the side, near to a specific structure, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;placement="side"&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placementBase="#[structure
            ID]"&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Values "left" and "right" are for those specific cases in which the
            specific placement on the right has a different legal meaning that a placement on the left, or when both
            types of placements exists in the same document (a rare occurrence indeed, but they exist).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New popup pattern&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;A new pattern was identified, and added both to the conceptual model
            of patterns, and to the vocabulary of elements in Akoma Ntoso. The pattern is called popup, and represents
            elements that, within the inline flow of text, create full and fully independent structures, that does not
            meddle nor interact with the text and inline elements that surround them. The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;quotedStructure
            &lt;/span&gt;element, which in past versions of the language did not belong to any pattern (being an
            exception), now fully belongs to the new popup pattern. A new element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;inlineNote&lt;/span&gt;
            has been added belonging to the same pattern, for notes whose content is placed alongside the text to which
            it refer. &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;inlineNote&lt;/span&gt; elements cannot be used to editorial
            content, but only for authoritative content that, for some reason, is placed in a note. Finally, the generic
            popup element has been added for any local extension to the language that needs to use popups.&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Parallel speech&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Support for parallel speech elements was added. This happens through
            new values for the attribute status (that now include “translated”, “edited”, “verbatim”, “ignore” (for
            incomplete structures in authoritative documents such as amendments) and a new attribute &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;“alternativeTo”&lt;/span&gt; that has been added to all content elements to specify
            separate and parallel copies of the same structure, that are present in the same document for a number of
            reasons:&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;ol&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;multi-lingual documents that contain the same structures in different languages.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt; multi-version documents that contain the same structures in different versions.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;multiple transcriptions, that contain the same speech in different transcriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;br/&gt;For instance:&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;

            &lt;speech id="sp1" by="#fv" status="verbatim"&gt;
            &lt;from&gt;Fabio Vitali&lt;/from&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Questo è il mio discorso in Italiano&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/speech&gt;

            &lt;speech id="sp1-alt1" by="#fv" status="translated" alternativeTo="#sp1"&gt;
            &lt;from&gt;Fabio Vitali&lt;/from&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This is my speech in Italian&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/speech&gt;

            &lt;/xmp&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Votes and quorum&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Two new inline elements are added to identify parts of the debate document, vote
            and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;utcome.&lt;/span&gt; These are
            meant to mark in the document the fragments of the text that describe a vote or the outcome of a vote.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt; parliamentary&lt;/span&gt; allows analysis
            on votes and quorum verifications that are present in a debate. It is possible to associate summaries of the
            outcome of a vote in a operable way, as follows:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;

            &lt;parliamentary&gt;
            &lt;voting id="vot1" href="#smr1" refersTo="#billAppr" outcome="#approved"&gt;
            &lt;quorum id="vot1-quo1" refersTo="#majority" value="50"/&gt;
            &lt;count id="vot1-cnt1" refersTo="#yeah" href="#qt1" value="41"/&gt;
            &lt;count id="vot1-cnt2" refersTo="#nay" href="#qt2" value="34"/&gt;
            &lt;count id="vot1-cnt3" refersTo="#nulls" href="#span147" value="23"/&gt;
            &lt;/voting&gt;
            &lt;/parliamentary&gt;

            ...

            &lt;summary id="smr1"&gt; Bill put to approval:
            &lt;quantity refersTo="#votes" id="qt1"&gt;34&lt;/quantity&gt; negative votes and
            &lt;quantity refersTo="#votes" id="qt2"&gt;41&lt;/quantity&gt; positive votes and
            &lt;quantity refersTo="#votes" id="qt3"&gt;23&lt;/quantity&gt; null votes, final result agreed.
            &lt;/summary&gt;
            &lt;/xmp&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Renumbering&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;a new core attribute, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;evolvingId&lt;/span&gt;, has
            been added to all elements to specify an identifier that can change from expression to expression after
            modifications, renumbering or coexistence of similarly named structures. A full explanation of it is put in
            the new section 7.4 of this document&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Changes in metadata section&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new metadata section, presentation, has been added for the drafting of important
            presentation specifications (e.g. for tables and typographical rules mandated by law) using any language
            (including CSS styles).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element analysis has an additional parliamentary block for &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;parliamentary &lt;/span&gt;analysis and an optional and repeatable element &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;otherAnalysis &lt;/span&gt;block for all other kinds of analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Former Top Level Class Place is now called Location. Similarly the TLC element
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCPlace&lt;/span&gt; is now known as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCLocation&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;In order to make room for an event element in the list of semantic inline
            elements, former element event within the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;lifecycle &lt;/span&gt;element is
            now called &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;eventRef.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element publication in the metadata is now optional (to allow for unpublished
            documents such as individual amendments).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Elements event and step, in lifecycle and workflow respectively, can now contain
            any non-AkomaNtoso elements inside. Attribute originatingExpression (yes/no) can now be used in events to
            specify that the event being referred to is the one from which this specific Expression originated.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new attribute pos has been added in all argument elements so that they can now
            make a more precise reference to the elements to which they are attached.Changes in introductory elements&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Changes in introductory elements&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;New preface-level elements: Some new elements have been added to use in prefaces:
            d&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ocCommittee, docIntroducer, docStage, docStatus, docJurisdiction&lt;/span&gt;,
            which are meant to be wrapped around the Committee, the introducer, the displayed stage, the displayed
            status and the displayed jurisdiction of the document being marked up. Again it is worth remembering that
            preface-level elements are to be used whenever in the official copy of the document these information bits
            are actually present, and not as a way to specify the information that is for any reason missing in the
            final copy of the text. Missing information is best specified in the appropriate structures of the metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The content model of elements preface and preamble have been enhanced. Besides
            allowing blocks, preface and preamble now allow subdivisions called recitals and citations for preamble, and
            longTitle for preface. Element subdivision is a generic element for a preface/preamble substructure, while
            the element formerly known as subdivision (in debates) is now called debateSection.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new coverpage element has been added to specify content that is relevant to the
            document and that is present in the cover page.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New inline elements&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element has been added, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;quantity&lt;/span&gt;,
            to contain quantitative fragments (e.g., numbers, amounts, etc.) that are relevant to the analysis of the
            text, Attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;normalized &lt;/span&gt;allows to markup the numerical content
            of the element if it is not directly perceivable in its original form (i.e. it is written in letters, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;placeholder,&lt;/span&gt; has
            been added to specify formulaic text structures that can be modified at will during the lifecycle of the
            document even not-authorially (e.g., a sentence such as ’30 days after the publication of this directive’
            converted in an actual date once the publication date of the directive is known). The attribute &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;originalText &lt;/span&gt;is used to specify the original text of the document after
            the replacement has taken place.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A complete specification of references to elements of the ontology has been added.
            Not only person, but now all elements of the Top Level Classes have their own element, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;person, organization, concept, object, event, location, process, role, term&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;entity&lt;/span&gt; is now fully a generic
            element and requires a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Two new inline elements have been added in the list of preface-specific elements:&lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt; legislature&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;session&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new preface inline element has been added, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;affectedDoc&lt;/span&gt;,
            to specify the document which is affected by this amendment.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element, relatedDoc, has been added for the document discussed within
            report documents.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element, change, has been added for the changes contained in the
            face-to-face text of an amendment.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new HTML element, u, has been added with similar use as in HTML, namely, to
            specify an underline.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;recordedTime&lt;/span&gt; is now an inline
            element and not a marker anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;popup&lt;/span&gt; content model available in
            elements such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;quotedStructure &lt;/span&gt;now allows also substructures of
            hierarchies such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;heading, num, content, citation, recital, intro&lt;/span&gt;
            and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;wrap &lt;/span&gt;to appear in it. Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;quotedStructure&lt;/span&gt;
            now has an additional attribute for that allows to associate individual &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;quotedStructures
            &lt;/span&gt;to individual &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;mod&lt;/span&gt; elements within a&lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt; mmod &lt;/span&gt;element.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New hierarchical element&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The fundamental structure of hierarchical elements has been modified introducing
            the intro and wrap elements, respectively before and after the content of the hierarchical elements, to
            specify introductory and concluding blocks to the lower levels of the containment hierarchy. This
            modification affects the list element, too.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new hierarchical element called &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;transitional &lt;/span&gt;has
            been added. This is meant to contain (often unnumbered or differently numbered) hierarchical items that,
            being of a transitional nature, are placed in a separate section called “transitional clauses” or some such
            name.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Three new hierarchical elements have been added, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;alinea,
            point &lt;/span&gt;and&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt; indent&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;New speech elements&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Two new elements have been added in the description of a debate: &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;narrative &lt;/span&gt;and summary. The narrative element is meant to contain all the
            narrative elements (that are not part of the scene description) that discuss things in the third person,
            rather than as report of a direct utterance from a participant. The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;summary
            &lt;/span&gt;element is meant to contain all the summarized description of speeches that are not transcribed
            verbatim because of their scarce relevance, formulaic nature, or other reasons. E.g.: “Question put and
            agreed to”.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Several new debate sections have been added to the list. They include: &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;rollCall, prayers, adjournement, oralStatements, writtenStatements, personalStatements,
            ministerialStatements, resolutions, and nationalInterest&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; was made optional.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;debate&lt;/span&gt; (that was the body of
            the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;debateRecord&lt;/span&gt; element) is now &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;debateContent&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;Various other changes&lt;/h4&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A number of bug fixes in content models of many elements, In particular, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;preface &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;conclusion&lt;/span&gt; are now
            optional everywhere, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;conclusion&lt;/span&gt; has become a fully hierarchical
            element just like &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;preface&lt;/span&gt; and&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;
            preamble&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;intro &lt;/span&gt;does not belong to the
            content model of element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;component &lt;/span&gt;anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;table&lt;/span&gt; has now an additional
            optional caption element as in HTML. Also, the id of HTML elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;tr,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;th&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;td&lt;/span&gt; is now
            optional to reduce the tear in specifying ids for long lists of cells in tables.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;Content model of element&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;td&lt;/span&gt;: So far, the content model of table cells followed the inline content
            model (i.e., the table cell was comparable to a single paragraph). This was felt inadequate because of the
            lack of support of multi-paragraph table cells, as well as cells that contain whole structures, such as
            articles, sections, etc. The element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;td&lt;/span&gt; has thus changed the
            relevant pattern, being upgraded from block to container. Now any container, or block can be contained in&lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt; td&lt;/span&gt; elements, but not next nor inline elements.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;New content model of&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;: the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;list &lt;/span&gt;element now
            allow for the specification of a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;listIntroduction &lt;/span&gt;element, a
            block element appearing before the first &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;, and of
            listConclusion, a block element appearing after the last &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; of
            the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;list&lt;/span&gt; (in Italian legal system, they correspond to alinea and
            conclusion, which are frequent occurrences in legal texts).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release incorporates several major changes to the schema. As described
            above these changes include additions, modifications and deletions. As such the number of changes is too
            great to produce a meaningful diff (comparison) document to show the cdifferences between this release and
            the previous one.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff></diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas2.0/akomantoso20.xsd?spec=svn160&amp;r=160</source>
    </release>
    <release number="12">
        <title>Diff:Oct 2009 &amp; Dec 2009</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release contains just two minor bug fixes:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The complex Type &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;AnyOtherType&lt;/span&gt; (allowing
            elements of any namespace except Akoma Ntoso) now allows any number (including zero) of
            elements instead of exactly one. This affects a number of metadata elements. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; now expects an URI
            instead of an IDREF value. This means that references to locations inside the document
            (e.g., in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;references&lt;/span&gt; section) now need to be prefixed
            with character “#” instead of being bare (e.g. &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo=”foobar”
            &lt;/span&gt;needs to become &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo=”#foobar”&lt;/span&gt;). This is in
            accordance to a general avoidance of the IDREF introduced on the 23/10/2006 release and
            for some reasons ignored for the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; attribute.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn133&amp;old=133&amp;r=137&amp;format=side&amp;path=%2Frelease%2Ftrunk%2Fschemas%2Fakomantoso10.xsd</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn133&amp;r=137</source>
    </release>
    <release number="11">
        <title>Diff:May 2009 &amp; Oct 2009</title>
        <notes>&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release contains some differences to previous versions regarding
            mainly the handling of judgments. Most differences regard metadata to analyze judgments, and
            only a few of them affect the document content.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docketNumber&lt;/span&gt;, has
            been introduced to handle the specification of the docket number, case number, file
            number or in general any number that represents the overall procedure of which this is
            one document. The term docketNumber has been chosen because it is clear, unambiguous,
            not overly restrictive (as would have been caseNumber) and not misunderstandable for a
            computer-related term (as would have been fileNumber).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Speech-related containers such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;administrationOfOaths&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;declarationOfVote&lt;/span&gt;,
            etc. have been added to the list of containers that can be specified anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element lawyer has a few difference in its attributes: the attribute
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;represents&lt;/span&gt; has become &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;for&lt;/span&gt;, and a new attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;empoweredBy&lt;/span&gt; has been
            added for lawyers that receive the representation not directly from the client but
            indirectly through a delegation of power via another lawyer.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;opinion&lt;/span&gt;, wrapping the opinion
            of
            the judges in a judgment, has a new attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; that
            specifies whether each individual judge consents or dissents from the judgment.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;workflow&lt;/span&gt; has been
            clarified.
            A &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;workflow&lt;/span&gt; is not composed of &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;action&lt;/span&gt; elements anymore, but of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;step&lt;/span&gt;
            elements. Each &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;step&lt;/span&gt; element defines (references to
            instances of) a date, an actor (either a TLCPerson or a TLCOrganization), a role (a
            TLCRole), and an outcome (a TLCConcept).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new analysis container has been added for judicial analysis. The
            element, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judicial&lt;/span&gt;, contains a number of judicial
            arguments, each of which connects a structure of the document to external sources or
            other structures of the document itself. The judicial element contains one result
            element that specifies the actual result of the judgment (one of &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;deny, dismiss, uphold, revert, replaceOrder, remit, decide,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;approve&lt;/span&gt;), and as many elements as needed of the judicial
            argument category, which are: s&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;upports,&#160; isAnalogTo,
            applies, extends, restricts, derogates, contrasts, overrules, dissentsFrom,
            putsInQuestion, distinguishes&lt;/span&gt;. It should be noted that the term &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;putsInQuestion&lt;/span&gt; is hardly satisfactory, and different from
            the proposed &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;questions&lt;/span&gt;, which cannot be used in this
            context because&#160; it is already used as a section of the Speech containers.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?path=/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;format=side&amp;r=133</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn133&amp;r=133</source>
    </release>
    <release number="10">
        <title>Diff:Mar 2009 &amp; May 2009</title>
        <notes>&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release contains no difference from the previous release but a few
            bug fix. The main justification of this release is to introduce systematic inline
            documentation to all structures of the language (groups, attribute groups, simple type,
            complex types and elements.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Additionally, a few bug fixes have been introduced:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The internal date of the schema has been updated to reflect correctly
            the revision date of the schema. In previous release, in fact, the release date within
            the schema had not been updated, resulting in two very different schemas asserting to
            have been last updated on the same date.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Group &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"&gt;ANotherInline&lt;/span&gt; has been
            actually
            added to the &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"&gt;inlineCM&lt;/span&gt; group , allowing elements &lt;span
            class="xmlparagraph"&gt;entity&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; to be
            actually used in document markup.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;&lt;span class="xmlparagraph"&gt;Complex types&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"&gt;anyOther&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"
            &gt;anyOtherType&lt;/span&gt;, which were identical, have been brought together into &lt;span
            class="xmlparagraph"&gt;one type&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlparagraph"
            &gt;anyOtherType&lt;/span&gt;. All elements and attributes have been updated accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Several reshuffles of relative position of definitions have been made.
            No difference in content has been performed, though.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn120&amp;r=120&amp;format=side&amp;path=/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=118</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn120&amp;r=120</source>
    </release>
    <release number="9">
        <title>Diff:Nov 2008 &amp; Mar 2009</title>
        <notes>&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This is a major release, providing a number of relevant modifications
            to the previous releases. &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Many of these modifications are
            NOT backward-compatible&lt;/span&gt;. These will be explicitly noted as such in the
            following.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;9.1.1 Sidenotes and out of
            line
            texts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;A completely new take on side notes has been undertaken in this
            release. Rather than being header blocks at the beginning of hierarchical structures, side
            notes are now full members of a new category: authorial notes. An authorial note is by
            definition a note (i.e., an out-of-line text fragment) that was provided by the original
            author of the content (i.e., by the author of the specific FRBR expression).&#160;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Thus the element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;sideNote&lt;/span&gt; has been
            removed, and substituted by a new container element, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;outOfLine&lt;/span&gt;, contained in a collection element &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;outOfLines&lt;/span&gt;. Each &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;outOfLine&lt;/span&gt; has a type attribute
            assuming either of the value &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;sideNote&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;publicationNote&lt;/span&gt;, an &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;href&lt;/span&gt;
            attribute pointing to a structure in the document to which the out of line text should be
            attached to, and contains blocks such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; elements.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Thus the fragment&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;
            &lt;akomaNtoso xmlns="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"&gt;
            &lt;act&gt;
            ...
            &#160; &lt;body&gt;
            &#160;&#160;&#160; &lt;section id="sect54.a"&gt;
            &lt;num&gt;54A&lt;/num&gt;
            &lt;heading&gt;Conduct of prosecutions.&lt;/heading&gt;
            &lt;clause id="sect54.a-cla1"&gt;
            &lt;num&gt;(1)&lt;/num&gt;
            &lt;sideNote&gt;Cap 75.&lt;/sideNote&gt;
            &lt;content&gt;
            &lt;p&gt; Blah blah&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/content&gt;
            &lt;/clause&gt;
            &lt;/section&gt;
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;/act&gt;
            &lt;/akomaNtoso&gt;&lt;/xmp&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;needs to become:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="xmlparagraph"&gt;&lt;xmp&gt;

            &lt;akomaNtoso xmlns="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"&gt;
            &lt;act&gt;
            ...
            &lt;body&gt;
            &lt;section id="sect54.a"&gt;
            &lt;num&gt;54A&lt;/num&gt;
            &lt;heading&gt;Conduct of prosecutions.&lt;/heading&gt;
            &lt;clause id="sect54.a-cla1"&gt;
            &lt;num&gt;(1)&lt;/num&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;content&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p&gt; Blah blah&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/content&gt;
            &lt;/clause&gt;
            &lt;/section&gt;
            &lt;/body&gt;
            &lt;outOfLines&gt;
            &lt;outOfLine id="out01" type="sideNote" href="#sect54.a-cla1"&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Cap 75.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/outOfLine&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;/outOfLines&gt;
            &lt;/act&gt;
            &lt;/akomaNtoso&gt;

            &lt;/xmp&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Please note three issues:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Reference direction is reversed than with footnotes: rather than the
            inline content referring to the note, it is the side note referring to the structural
            fragment it appears with. This allows to get rid of reference markers within the text,
            and makes more sense in an abstract sense.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Only referable structures can have a side note. This means that side
            notes are to be considered associated to sections, clauses, etc. and not to the text
            they contain. If a fragment of text needs to have a side note, it must be wrapped in a
            referable fragment, such as a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ref&lt;/span&gt; or a &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;span&lt;/span&gt; element.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;While the previous &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;sideNote&lt;/span&gt; element was
            a
            block, and thus could contain directly text, the &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;outOfLine&lt;/span&gt; element is a container, and thus must contain one or more blocks
            that in turn contain text.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This modification is &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;NOT
            backward-compatible. Elements have been removed and a whole new section created in all
            types of documents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;
            &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.1.2 Content model reorganization for speeches&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After being shown an Australian judgement that was really a
            dialogue between the judge and the lawyers, and considering that AKOMA NTOSO already has all
            the necessary elements to deal with dialogues, only they were not available in judgements,
            it was decided that all speech elements should now be available everywhere a container is
            available. Thus elements such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;speech&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;question&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;answer&lt;/span&gt; are now
            available even in &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgements&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This modification &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;IS
            backward-compatible. Content models have been expanded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph" style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;9.1.3 New inline elements&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A number of new inline elements have been added to this
            release:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;lawyer&lt;/span&gt; is used to mark the
            specification of a lawyer. Attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;represents&lt;/span&gt; can be
            used to refer to the party it represents and the attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;role&lt;/span&gt; can be added to provide more detailed information about the kind of
            lawyer.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;opinion&lt;/span&gt; is used to specify the
            opinion of the individual judge within the coram of a judgement. Use attribute &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; to point to a &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;TLCConcept&lt;/span&gt; that provides computable assessment of the type of opinion held
            by the judge.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;signature&lt;/span&gt; is used to specify
            the
            presence of a signature in the document. Use attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; to point to a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCPerson&lt;/span&gt; that
            provides the identification of the person responsible of the signature.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;entity&lt;/span&gt; is used to wrap any
            mention to a concept that is worth being mentioned in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;references&lt;/span&gt; section. This includes persons, organizations, roles, and places,
            among others. Always use attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; to point to a
            Top Level Class element in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;references&lt;/span&gt; section that
            provides computable assessment of the concept associated to that element.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; is used to wrap explicit
            dates in the document (that are not &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;documentDates&lt;/span&gt;). Use
            attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; to provide an unambiguous form of the date
            in XSD 1.0 syntax yyyy-mm-dd. Use attribute&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt; refersTo&lt;/span&gt;, if
            appropriate, to point to a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCEvent&lt;/span&gt; that provides
            computable assessment of the event associated to that date. Please note that a &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; element was already present in the schema in the
            identification section of the metadata, and that it has now been renamed &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRdate&lt;/span&gt; (see section 9.1.5).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This modification &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;IS
            backward-compatible. Elements have been added.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p style="font-weight: bold;" class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.1.4 Judgement-specific and
            act-specific elements reunited&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgementType&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;judgementTitle&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;judgementNumber&lt;/span&gt; were considered overlapping and redundant with respect to &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;documentType&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;documentTitle&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;documentNumber&lt;/span&gt;, and thus removed. Judgements should now
            use these documents. Furthermore, a new section in the Release Notes has been added
            providing hints at how to use these elements, section 7.2, that specifies that these
            elements may be present multiple times in the document, but if there are more than one per
            type, then the attribute refersTo must be present and point to different instances of
            TLCConcepts.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This modification is &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;NOT
            backward-compatible. Elements have been removed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;p style="font-weight: bold;" class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.1.5 Name changes in metadata
            elements&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Elements within &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRWork&lt;/span&gt;,&#160;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRExpression&lt;/span&gt; , &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;FRBRManifestation,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRItem&lt;/span&gt; have now an
            added
            FRBR prefix, and thus were turned from &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;this,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;uri,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;alias,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;date,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;author&lt;/span&gt; to
            &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRthis&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRuri,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRalias,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRdate,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRauthor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;A new element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; was added, and
            its
            name clashed with the elements within the FRBR levels. Given the philosophy of giving short
            names to elements within the content, and longer names to elements within the metadata, it
            was decided to change the name of the FRBR elements, and of all it neighbors, by introducing
            the same FRBR prefix for all.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This modification is &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;NOT
            backward-compatible. Element names have been changed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;
            &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;9.1.6 Bug fixes&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A few elements now required presence of two main attributes: &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo.&lt;/span&gt; These are
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;*ref&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;*mod&lt;/span&gt;
            elements, plus elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;party,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judge&lt;/span&gt; and the new element &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;lawyer.&lt;/span&gt; Previously both id and refersTo were optional. This modification is
            NOT backward-compatible. Attributes have been made required.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;scene&lt;/span&gt; was previously present as
            both a container and a block. This is an error, and has been fixed. Element &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;scene&lt;/span&gt; is now only a container available everywhere a
            container can be specified. &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;This modification is NOT
            backward-compatible, but minor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn120&amp;r=118&amp;format=side&amp;path=/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=111</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn118&amp;r=118</source>
    </release>
    <release number="8">
        <title>Diff:Mar 2008 &amp; Nov 2008</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release comprises a major modification in naming of elements,
            introducing a systematic usage of&#160; camel case, settling a long-standing issue about
            incoherence in the usage of lower and uppercase characters in element names (as well as one
            element group). This change is thus fixing an overall problem of coherence in element
            naming, rather than a concrete problem of descriptiveness or completeness of the
            vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Content differences:&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The spelling &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;“judgment”&lt;/span&gt; has been
            replaced
            with &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;“judgement”&lt;/span&gt; in observance to the above-mentioned
            mail by Mariya Badeva. This relates to all elements and attributes containing the word
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;All Top Level Classes have now a proposed syntax for IDs (that was up to
            this day only mentioned as TBD).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;comment&lt;/span&gt; has been renamed &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;scene&lt;/span&gt; according to remarks about adopting a vocabulary more
            connected to screenplays.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActTitle,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActNumber,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActProponent,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActDate,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ActPurpose&lt;/span&gt;
            have been renamed &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docTitle,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docNumber,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docProponent,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docDate,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;docPurpose&lt;/span&gt;
            so
            as to reflect a vocabulary apt to describe more than just legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;recordedTime&lt;/span&gt; has now a new
            attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; to allow for the specification of recorded
            times for the beginning of event (&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;startEvent&lt;/span&gt;) and end of
            events (&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;endEvent&lt;/span&gt;) if necessary&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new inline element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;remark&lt;/span&gt; has been
            added to specify editorial inclusions within the main text (for instance the caption of
            the speaker in the new page continuing from the previous one). An attribute type with an
            initial list of remark types &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;(sceneDescription,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;phenomenon,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;caption,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;translation&lt;/span&gt;) is also added.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Case differences (specific to the camelCase
            release):&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A specific policy for case in names has been decided. It only and
            specifically regards structure names in the schema (these include names for attributes,
            elements, simple types, complex types, attribute groups and element groups) that are
            composed of two separate terms in plain English. The policy is as follows:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="secondlevel_bullets"&gt;A name that is composed of a simple term is all in lowercase
            (e.g., &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;section,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;act,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;publication&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="secondlevel_bullets"&gt;A name that is composed of two or more full terms has the
            first one in lowercase, and all the others have their initial letter in uppercase (that
            I call camelCase, as a reduced form of CamelCase). For instance, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;courtType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;actDate,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;mainContent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="secondlevel_bullets"&gt;A name that is composed of an acronym plus one or more full
            terms has the acronym in all capital letters and the remaining terms in camelCase (i.e.,
            the first is all lowercase and the others have the first letter in uppercase). For
            instance, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRManifestation,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCPerson.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The element groups, complex types and simple types &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;EventType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;VersionType&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;InlineCM&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;SpeechSection&lt;/span&gt;,&#160; &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;HierarchicalStructure&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;OpenStructure,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;DebateStructure,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;JudgmentStructure&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;DocumentTypes&lt;/span&gt; are now &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;eventType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;iversionType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;inlineCM,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;speechSection,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;hierarchicalStructure,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;openStructure,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;debateStructure,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgementStructure&lt;/span&gt; (note new spelling for judgement) and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;documentType&lt;/span&gt; (note, also singular now) in
            camelCase.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;17 elements have changed their case in order to adopt the camelCase
            approach: elements activeModifications, activeRef, akomaNtoso, attachmentOf,
            debateRecord, efficacyMod, forceMod, hasAttachment, mainContent, meaningMod, noteRef,
            passiveModifications, passiveRef, proceduralMotions, scopeMod, textualMod, and
            tocItem.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;

        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn111&amp;r=111&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn111&amp;r=111</source>
    </release>
    <release number="7">
        <title>Diff:Oct 2007 &amp; Mar 2008</title>
        <notes>&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This is a tentative release of a major evolution, with a specific
            improvement, namely the support for judgments. Other minor modifications have been included.
            Existing documents that are not judgments should be unaffected by this release.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Most of the modifications accept and organize the proposal from Monica
            Palmirani in a document called “Common Open Standard for Judgments”.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Modifications unrelated to the judgment we find:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new element for debate documents called &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;DeclarationofVote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new element this is added in all FRBR levels to report the URI of the
            specific component where the metadata block is found&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The name for the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Attachment&lt;/span&gt; element in
            the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;analysis&lt;/span&gt; element is now &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;HasAttachment&lt;/span&gt; in order to avoid confusions.&#160;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Modifications related to the judgment as specified in Palmirani’s
            document are:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new document type &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;“judgement”&lt;/span&gt; is
            introduced, that has its own schema composed of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;meta,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;header,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentBody,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;conclusions&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;attachment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Within the section &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;header&lt;/span&gt; a number of
            additional inline-level purpose-specific elements have been added, namely: &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentTitle,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentNumber,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;courtType,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;neutralCitation,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;party,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judge,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;judgmentDate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentBody&lt;/span&gt; has a repeatable
            choice
            of sections named &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;introduction,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;background,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;motivation,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;decision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;An additional metadata element, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;workflow,&lt;/span&gt;
            and its repeatable child &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;action&lt;/span&gt; have been added.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Some modifications diverge from Palmirani’s proposal, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;No elements such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;coram,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judges&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentDates&lt;/span&gt;
            have been specified, as they are containers, disallowed in the patterned structure of
            inline elements. The corresponding singular elements are used directly in the flow of
            the text.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; has been substituted
            with &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judgmentBody,&lt;/span&gt; as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;
            has been used already to refer to the content of hierarchical structures such as acts
            and bills.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;href&lt;/span&gt; attributes in &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;part,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;judge&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;action,&lt;/span&gt;
            meant to
            refer to the ontological section references, have been omitted as the proper attribute
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo&lt;/span&gt; now exist for all elements in the schema,
            and therefore no need for such attribute was needed. The &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;as&lt;/span&gt; attribute, on the other hand, has been kept as proposed.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Open issues are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;We have adopted the spelling “judgment” instead of “judgement” as
            proposed by Palmirani, but we are worried about the last sentence in the following
            fragment from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judgment_%28law%29" class="bodylink"
            &gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judgment_%28law%29&lt;/a&gt;: “However, the spelling
            judgement (with e added) largely replaced judgment in the United Kingdom in a non-legal
            context […] In the context of the law and theology, however, judgment is preferred. In
            the U.S. judgment strongly prevails. As with many such spelling differences, both forms
            are equally acceptable in Canada and Australia, although judgment is more common in
            Canada and judgement in Australia.[1] In New Zealand the form judgment is the preferred
            spelling in dictionaries, newspapers and legislation, although the variant judgement can
            also be found in all three categories. In South Africa, judgement is the more common
            form."&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;We are not convinced of the need for a &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;workflow&lt;/span&gt; element, and would have preferred to have it harmonized and
            included in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;lifecycle&lt;/span&gt; element.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn109&amp;r=109&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/release/trunk/schemas/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn136&amp;r=33</source>
    </release>
    <release number="6">
        <title>Diff:Sep 2007 &amp; Oct 2007</title>
        <notes>&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;
            &lt;div class="paragraph-body"&gt;
            &lt;div class="plain"&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This is a major release with plenty of differences and
            improvement. It is worth noting that at least ONE modification (the creation of the
            content element and the renaming of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;title&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;subtitle&lt;/span&gt;) is NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE, so that documents
            that were valid against the previous versions most probably will NOT be valid
            against this version.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;Please note the modifications that are not backward compatible
            are still amenable of automatic conversion. I have added an XSLT stylesheet that
            takes a valid Akoma Ntoso document of the previous release and converts it into a
            valid document of the current release. You can find it in the styles directory of
            the release, called &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;convertToThis.xsl.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p class="bodyparagraph"&gt;This release also includes and documents an unofficial,
            undocumented release called &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Tentative Release
            20071510&lt;/span&gt; dated 15 October, 2007.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;clauses &lt;/span&gt;has been renamed
            into &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;. NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;title &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;subtitle &lt;/span&gt;are now called &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;heading &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;subheading&lt;/span&gt;, to allow for
            the presence of the title hierarchical elements. NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The list of hierarchical elements is enriched with the addition
            of elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;book&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;tome&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;subsection&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;subpart&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;subparagraph&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;subchapter&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;subtitle&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;subclause&lt;/span&gt;. As mentioned, elements &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;title &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;subtitle
            &lt;/span&gt;existed for a different purpose, and are now plain hierarchical
            elements.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;content &lt;/span&gt;is added to
            connect the list of hierarchical elements to their actual textual content. Any
            hierarchical element can contain either other hierarchical elements or the &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;content &lt;/span&gt;element which contains blocks. NOT BACKWARD
            COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The content model of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;article &lt;/span&gt;and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;clause &lt;/span&gt;has completely changed and is now
            identical to the other hierarchical elements. NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new optional attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo
            &lt;/span&gt;has been added to all content elements of the Akoma Ntoso schema. The
            attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo &lt;/span&gt;can be used when necessary to
            refer to an element of the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;references&lt;/span&gt; section, in
            order to suggest an ontological interpretation of the content of the element.
            Also use &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;refersTo &lt;/span&gt;to make an element equivalent
            and referring to another (e.g. for translation purposes).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;A new value for the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;status
            &lt;/span&gt;attribute has been added, “editorial”. The new value is to be added for
            content that has to appear in the final document with the rest of the text, but
            was not originally included in the document created by the author. Editorial
            elements can be used for editorial annotations (e.g.: &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;&lt;span status=”editorial”&gt;(Translation of Afrikaans paragraph
            follows.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;An initial list of &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;debaterecord
            &lt;/span&gt;subdivisions has been created. Debate records can now be organized with
            subdivisions that reflect the actual nature of the content. The new elements
            are: &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;AdministrationOfOath&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Communication&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Petitions&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Papers&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;NoticesOfMotion&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Questions&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;ProceduralMotions&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;PointOfOrder&lt;/span&gt;, and can be used in all places where previously only
            subdivision could be used. TENTATIVE MODIFICATION. DO NOT RELY ON THIS.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To avoid confusion between the elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;item &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;, the latter has been
            renamed &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRItem&lt;/span&gt;. For symmetry, all four FRBR
            levels have similarly changed name. Therefore &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Work&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Expression&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Manifestation &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Item
            &lt;/span&gt;are now called &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRork&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRExpression&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;FRBRManifestation &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;FRBRItem&lt;/span&gt;. NOT
            BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;To avoid confusion between the elements &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;force &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Force&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;efficacy &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Efficacy&lt;/span&gt;, the latter ones have been renamed &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;ForceMod &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;EfficacyMod&lt;/span&gt;. For
            symmetry, all other modification elements have similarly changed name. Therefore
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Textual&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Meaning&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Scope&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Force&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Efficacy &lt;/span&gt;and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;LegalSystem &lt;/span&gt;are now called &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;TextualMod&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;MeaningMod&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;ScopeMod&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;ForceMod&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;EfficacyMod
            &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;LegalSystemMod&lt;/span&gt;. NOT BACKWARD
            COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;uri &lt;/span&gt;element specifies the URI
            in a &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;value &lt;/span&gt;attribute rather than in an &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;href &lt;/span&gt;attribute. (Bug fix from previous error) NOT
            BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The value &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Suspension &lt;/span&gt;for the
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;type &lt;/span&gt;attribute of the &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;EfficacyMod &lt;/span&gt;(formerly &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Efficacy&lt;/span&gt;)
            element&#160; has been replaced by two values, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;EntryIntoEfficacy &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;EndOfEfficacy&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;All TLC are now present in the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;reference
            &lt;/span&gt;section. Newly added terms are: &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;TLCConcept&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCObject&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCEvent&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCPlace&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCProcess&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;TLCRole&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCTerm&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Existing TLC elements have been renamed to include the prefix
            “TLC” to clarify their role. This include the renaming of &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Person&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;Organization&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Role&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Reference &lt;/span&gt;into &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;TLCPerson&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCOrganization&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCRole&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;TLCReference&lt;/span&gt;. NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;TLCReference &lt;/span&gt;(formerly
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Reference) &lt;/span&gt;is now a generic element in all
            respects, and has a new required &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;name &lt;/span&gt;attribute.
            NOT BACKWARD COMPATIBLE&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;The &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Work &lt;/span&gt;element now contains
            components just like the other elements of the &lt;span class="xmlinline"
            &gt;identification &lt;/span&gt;element, such as &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Expression,
            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Manifestation &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span
            class="xmlinline"&gt;Item &lt;/span&gt;(Added in &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Tentative
            Release 20071510&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li class="bullets"&gt;Within the &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;identification
            &lt;/span&gt;elements, &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;component &lt;/span&gt;can now nest and
            contain other &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;component &lt;/span&gt;elements&#160; (Added in
            &lt;span class="xmlinline"&gt;Tentative Release 20071510&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;

            &lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn107&amp;r=107&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=105</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn107&amp;r=107</source>
    </release>
    <release number="5">
        <title>Diff:Jun 2007 &amp; Sep 2007</title>
        <notes>&lt;div style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);" colspan="1" rowspan="1" align="left" width="20%"&gt;This
            is a minor bug-fix release
            managing better the interaction between Akoma Ntoso elements and
            elements coming from different vocabularies. &lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;br/&gt;
            The attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline">processContent&lt;/span&gt;
            of the &lt;span class="xmlinline">&lt;xsd:any&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            element is set to &lt;span class="xmlinline">lax&lt;/span&gt;, so
            that if proprietary elements are added here and there, users do not
            have to have the proprietary schema to validate the documents, but just
            the main Akoma Ntoso one.&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;br/&gt;
            A new &lt;span class="xmlinline">href&lt;/span&gt; attribute is
            added to a few inner elements of the provisions in the active
            modifications part of the metadata. This is to prevent the creation of
            useless proprietary elements&#160; to point to the positions in the
            document that contain the text being referenced.&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;</notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn105&amp;r=105&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=103</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn109&amp;r=105</source>
    </release>
    <release number="4">
        <title>Diff:Feb 2007 &amp; Jun 2007</title>
        <notes>&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;This is a bug-fix
            release for managing
            the expected content model of elements such as &lt;span class="xmlinline">mod,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span
            class="xmlinline">mmod,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline">rmod,&lt;/span&gt; which were expected
            to be
            mixed content model with a free choice of inline elements and quotes,
            and due to the odd behavior of complex type derivation through
            extension in XML Schema 1.0, ended up being a mixed content model with
            an ordered &lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;sequence&lt;/span&gt; of a free
            choice of inline elements and a free choice of quotes, in this order.
            Similar problem could be found with li elements. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;The solution has been to
            revoke the type of &lt;span class="xmlinline">mod, mmod&lt;/span&gt;
            and &lt;span class="xmlinline">rmod&lt;/span&gt; from being
            derivations of the inline type, and create a new type modType, which is
            disconnected from inline but has all the right elements. A similar
            solution has been taken for li. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;Also, for greater precision,
            the previously defined type &lt;span class="xmlinline">modType&lt;/span&gt;
            (which collected modification metadata) has been renamed &lt;span class="xmlinline">modificationType&lt;/span&gt;
            in order to
            prevent further confusion.&#160; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;Small bug fix in the content
            model of the &lt;span class="xmlinline">quotedStructure&lt;/span&gt;
            element that now allows &lt;span class="xmlinline">clause&lt;/span&gt;
            elements to be present.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;The examples and xslt
            stylesheets were changed to reflect changes in naming policies in
            metadata sections. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
            &lt;span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn103&amp;r=103&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=101</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn109&amp;r=103</source>
    </release>
    <release number="3">
        <title>Diff:Nov 2006 &amp; Feb 2007</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;" colspan="3" rowspan="1"&gt;The Naming Convention is introduced and
            officially raised to standard level. Correspondingly, section 10 of this document has been
            mostly emptied and now refers to the external document “AKOMA NTOSO Naming Convention”.
            &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The element and attribute synopsis has been completely revised and reorganized.
            &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The schema only received minor modifications covering only the rename of the
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">minutes&lt;/span&gt; element into debaterecord, a few bug fixes in
            attributes, plus the support for differences in force and efficacy periods (&lt;span
            style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Please note&lt;/span&gt;: an intermediate, non official release dated
            30/11/2006 already contains some of these modifications). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two new core
            optional
            attributes, &lt;span class="xmlinline">startEfficacy&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">endEfficacy,&lt;/span&gt; have been added to all content
            elements. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elements &lt;span class="xmlinline">list,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">ul, ol&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="xmlinline">table&lt;/span&gt; now have
            the full set of core
            attributes, i.e., &lt;span class="xmlinline">id, class, style, title&lt;/span&gt;,
            and enactment attributes. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Element
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">ActDate&lt;/span&gt; now has a &lt;span class="xmlinline">date&lt;/span&gt;
            attribute
            for normalized dates. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A bug in the content model of
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">mod, mmod&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">rmod&lt;/span&gt; has been fixed and now their content
            model allows plain text to be inserted as well as other types of content.
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn101&amp;r=101&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=99</diff>
        <source>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn101&amp;r=101</source>
    </release>
    <release number="2">
        <title>Diff:Oct 2006 &amp; Nov 2006</title>
        <notes>&lt;div style="text-align: justify;" colspan="4" rowspan="1"&gt;A minor release covering mostly only the
            attributes and elements of the metadata section. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elements
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">attachments, clauses, debate&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">maincontent&lt;/span&gt; now have the core set of
            attributes (they were forgotten in previous versions). &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Analysis&lt;/span&gt; now distinguish between active
            modifications (stored in amending acts) and passive modifications (stored in amended
            acts). The old &lt;span class="xmlinline">amendments&lt;/span&gt; element has been
            replaced with &lt;span class="xmlinline">ActiveModifications&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">PassiveModifications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Attachment&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">AttachmentOf&lt;/span&gt; have a new attribute,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">type.&lt;/span&gt; No restricted set of values is foreseen
            yet, but this is bound to change in future release. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">source&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">destination&lt;/span&gt; elements of all analytical
            elements can now be repeated. The attribute
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">upTo&lt;/span&gt; has also been added to deal with range references for
            analytical
            elements. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two new attributes,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">exclusion&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline">incomplete,&lt;/span&gt;
            are
            added for modifications that are specified with exceptions and in an incomplete manner.
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A new textual modification has been added,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Renumbering.&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The elements &lt;span class="xmlinline">oldText&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">newText&lt;/span&gt; have been renamed into
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">old&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The element
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">condition&lt;/span&gt; has now a new &lt;span class="xmlinline">frozen&lt;/span&gt;
            attribute. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn99&amp;r=99&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=97</diff>
        <source>
            http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn99&amp;r=99
        </source>
    </release>
    <release number="1">
        <title>Diff:Jun 2006 &amp; Oct 2006</title>
        <notes>
            &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;
            &lt;div style="text-align: justify;" colspan="4" rowspan="1"&gt;Many major modifications have been brought
            into this release. Metadata are now completely reorganized, introducing the organization in four
            levels and a section on amendment analysis. Within document, new elements have been added to
            handle strange hierarchies, line and page numbering, and multiple and range-based modifications
            and references. In detail: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New block elements called
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt;,titled block (&lt;span class="xmlinline">tblock&lt;/span&gt;)
            and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">foreign&lt;/span&gt; are added.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;New inline elements
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">eol &lt;/span&gt;and &lt;span class="xmlinline">eop&lt;/span&gt; for managing
            end-of-line and end-of-page
            situations when they are relevant&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">IDREF&lt;/span&gt; attributes are now &lt;span class="xmlinline">ANYURI
            &lt;/span&gt;(thus allowing for references to be stored outside of the document). A reference
            to item foobar used to be &lt;span class="xmlinline">idref=”foobar”&lt;/span&gt;,
            needs now to be &lt;span class="xmlinline">href=”#foobar”&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The
            attribute &lt;span class="xmlinline">numbering&lt;/span&gt; has been removed because
            of doubts of its real usefulness. Can be reinstated if found needed. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two new
            elements appear close to &lt;span class="xmlinline">num&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">title&lt;/span&gt; at the beginning of hierarchical
            elements, &lt;span class="xmlinline">subtitle&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">sidenote&lt;/span&gt;. It’s left to markers to decide when
            to use either one. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The content model of all metadata elements has been
            simplified removing the attributes for style and enactment that made little sense for
            them. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Element &lt;span class="xmlinline">item&lt;/span&gt; has completely
            been reformulated. Its former role as plain member of a hierarchy of subdivision
            elements within &lt;span class="xmlinline">maincontent&lt;/span&gt; has been
            replaced by item &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt;, which &lt;span
            style="font-style: italic;"&gt;contains&lt;/span&gt; any of a number of
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">item&lt;/span&gt; elements. Use
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt; instead of
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">item&lt;/span&gt;, and place
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">item&lt;/span&gt; within
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">list&lt;/span&gt; elements. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elements
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">ref&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="xmlinline">
            mod&lt;/span&gt; have been enriched with derivative elements
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">mref&lt;/span&gt; (multiple references),
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">rref&lt;/span&gt; (range of references),
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">mmod&lt;/span&gt; (multiple modifications) and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">rmod&lt;/span&gt; (range of modifications) to manage
            references and modifications that explicitly list in brief multiple different locations
            of destination document (e.g., “The Provisions of sections 1(1) and (2), 24, 25, 29(2),
            30, 31, 43, 55, 56, 57, 58, 60, 61, 62, 63, 67, 80, 84, 92, 93, 94, 95, 96, 97, 98, 99,
            100, 101, 102, 103, 104, 105, 106, 107, 108 and 115 of law n° 92-10 of 17 september 1992
            to lay down the conditions governing the vacancy of and election to the Presidency of
            the Republic are amended and supplemented” and “The existing sections 34 to 54 of the
            Principal Act shall be amended by renumbering them as sections 33 to 53 respectively”).
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;New inline elements &lt;span class="xmlinline">ins&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">del&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">omissis&lt;/span&gt; are included for managing explicit newly inserted text,
            deleted text
            or omitted text in presentation of norms. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All HTML
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">table&lt;/span&gt; elements now have required id. HTML
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">li&lt;/span&gt; element has now optional value.
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The section &lt;span class="xmlinline">meta&lt;/span&gt; has been
            completely rewritten and has new a completely different structure and philosophy. See
            section 7 for details on how to use it. The structure splits open the old
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">descriptor&lt;/span&gt; section, which now is separated
            into &lt;span class="xmlinline">identification,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">publication&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">classification,&lt;/span&gt; and introduces the wholly new
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">analysis&lt;/span&gt; section. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Identification&lt;/span&gt; is a new structure that
            contains information about the URIs relative to the four levels of organization of
            metadata, &lt;span class="xmlinline">Work,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Expression,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Manifestation&lt;/span&gt; and
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Item.&lt;/span&gt; For each of these levels a number of
            metadata elements are required: &lt;span class="xmlinline">author,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">date,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">URI,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">components&lt;/span&gt; (except for
            &lt;span class="xmlinline">Work&lt;/span&gt;) and &lt;span class="xmlinline">preservation.&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="xmlinline">Analysis&lt;/span&gt; is a container of provisions
            about the actual content of the norm. Currently it contains only modification
            provisions, that are used to classify and manage amendment acts and documents. A total
            of 6 types of amendments have been added, for a total of 32 subcases, and a collection
            of 10 parameters to describe them. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        </notes>
        <diff>http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/diff?spec=svn97&amp;r=97&amp;format=side&amp;path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old_path=/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd&amp;old=94</diff>
        <source>
            http://code.google.com/p/akomantoso/source/browse/rel_history/trunk/akomantoso10.xsd?spec=svn97&amp;r=97
        </source>
    </release>
</releases>
